<?xml version="1.0"?>
<QtoSetDef xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://buildingSMART-tech.org/xml/psd/PSD_IFC4.xsd">
  <IfcVersion version="IFC4x2" />
  <Name>Qto_OpeningElementBaseQuantities</Name>
  <Definition>Base quantities that are common to the definition of all occurrences of opening elements.</Definition>
  <Applicability />
  <ApplicableClasses>
    <ClassName>IfcOpeningElement</ClassName>
  </ApplicableClasses>
  <ApplicableTypeValue>IfcOpeningElement</ApplicableTypeValue>
  <QtoDefs>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>Width</Name>
      <Definition>Width of the opening, in case of wall openings it is the horizontal dimension in case of slab openings it is one horizontal dimension. Only provided, if the area is rectangular.</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_LENGTH</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Breite</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Width</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">開口幅</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Breite der Önnung, bei Wandöffnugen ist es die horizontale Abmessung, bei Deckenöffnungen eine der beiden horizontalen Abmessungen. Wird nur dann angegeben, wenn die Öffnung rechteckig ist.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">開口の幅。壁の開口の場合、水平方向の寸法。スラブの開口の場合、一つの水平方向の寸法。形状が長方形の場合のみ与えられる。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>Height</Name>
      <Definition>Height of the opening, in case of wall openings it is the vertical dimension in case of slab openings it is one horizontal dimension. Only provided, if the area is rectangular. </Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_LENGTH</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Höhe</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Height</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">開口高さ</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Höhe der Önnung, bei Wandöffnugen ist es die vertikale Abmessung, bei Deckenöffnungen eine der beiden horizontalen Abmessungen. Wird nur dann angegeben, wenn die Öffnung rechteckig ist.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">開口の高さ。壁の開口の場合、垂直方向の寸法。スラブの開口の場合、一つの水平方向の寸法。形状が長方形の場合のみ与えられる。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>Depth</Name>
      <Definition>Depth (or thickness) of the opening, in case of openings it shall be identical to the width (or thickness) of the voided element, in case of recesses it shall be less. Only provided, if the depth is constant. </Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_LENGTH</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Tiefe</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Depth</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">開口奥行き</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Die Tiefe einer Öffnung, diese entspricht der Dicke des Elementes, in dem sich die Öffnung befindet. Wird nur dann angegeben, wenn das Element eine konstante Dicke hat.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">開口の奥行き（厚さ）。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>Area</Name>
      <Definition>Area of the opening as viewed by an elevation view (for wall openings) or as viewed by a ground floor view (for slab openings). </Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_AREA</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Fläche</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Area</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">面積</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Fläche der Öffnung, es ist die Ansichtsfläche für Wandöffnungen, oder die Grundfläche für Deckenöffnungen.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">開口の面積。立面図で見た場合の形状。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>Volume</Name>
      <Definition>Volume of the opening. It is the subtraction volume of the opening from the voided element (e.g. wall or slab). In case that the geometric volume of the opening is bigger then the subtraction volume, only the subtraction volume should be used. </Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_VOLUME</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Volumen</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Volume</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">体積</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Volumen der Öffnung. Es ist das Abzugsvolumen der Öffnung vom dem Element, in dem sich die Öffnung befindet. Sollte der Öffnungskörper eine größere Ausdehnung besitzen, wird nur das Abzugsvolumen berücksichtigt.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">開口の体積。壁やスラブなどから、穴が開いた部分の差の体積。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
  </QtoDefs>
  <QtoDefinitionAliases>
    <QtoDefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Basismengen für Öffnungen</QtoDefinitionAlias>
    <QtoDefinitionAlias lang="en" />
    <QtoDefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">開口に関わる共通の基本数量情報の定義。</QtoDefinitionAlias>
  </QtoDefinitionAliases>
</QtoSetDef>