<?xml version="1.0"?>
<QtoSetDef xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://buildingSMART-tech.org/xml/psd/PSD_IFC4.xsd">
  <IfcVersion version="IFC4x2" />
  <Name>Qto_RoofBaseQuantities</Name>
  <Definition>Base quantities that are common to the definition of all occurrences of roof.</Definition>
  <Applicability />
  <ApplicableClasses>
    <ClassName>IfcRoof</ClassName>
  </ApplicableClasses>
  <ApplicableTypeValue>IfcRoof</ApplicableTypeValue>
  <QtoDefs>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>GrossArea</Name>
      <Definition>Total gross area of the outer surface of the roof. It is the sum of all roof slab gross areas. Roof openings, like sky windows and other openings and cut-outs are not taken into account.</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_AREA</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Bruttofläche</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Gross Area</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamte Bruttofläche der Dachhaut (Ansichtsfläche senkrecht zur Dachneigung, oder Mantelfläche der Dachhaut bei gekrümmten, gewölbten Flächen, nicht jedoch die projizierte Fläche). Alle Öffnungen, wie z.B. Dachflächenfenster, werden übermessen.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>NetArea</Name>
      <Definition>Total net area of the outer surface of the roof. It is the suma of all roof slab net areas. Roof openings, like sky windows and other openings and cut-outs are taken into account.</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_AREA</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Nettofläche</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Net Area</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamte Nettofläche der Dachhaut (Ansichtsfläche senkrecht zur Dachneigung, oder Mantelfläche der Dachhaut bei gekrümmten, gewölbten Flächen, nicht jedoch die projizierte Fläche). Alle Öffnungen, wie z.B. Dachflächenfenster, werden abgezogen.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>ProjectedArea</Name>
      <Definition>Total gross area of the outer surfaces of the roof, projected tp the ground. It is the sum of all projected roof slab gross areas. Roof openings, like sky windows and other openings and cut-outs are not taken into account.</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_AREA</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">projizierte Fläche</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Projected Area</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamte Bruttofläche der Dachhaut als auf den Grundriss projizierte Fläche. Alle Öffnungen, wie z.B. Dachflächenfenster, werden übermessen.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
  </QtoDefs>
  <QtoDefinitionAliases>
    <QtoDefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Basismengen für alle Bauelemente vom Typ Dach.</QtoDefinitionAlias>
    <QtoDefinitionAlias lang="en" />
  </QtoDefinitionAliases>
</QtoSetDef>