<?xml version="1.0"?>
<PropertySetDef xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" ifdguid="9fc6c200d20811e1800000215ad4efdf" templatetype="PSET_TYPEDRIVENOVERRIDE" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://buildingSMART-tech.org/xml/psd/PSD_IFC4.xsd" xmlns="http://buildingSMART-tech.org/xml/psd/PSD_IFC4.xsd">
  <IfcVersion version="IFC4" />
  <Name>Pset_SpaceCommon</Name>
  <Definition>Properties common to the definition of all occurrences of IfcSpace. Please note that several space attributes are handled directly at the IfcSpace instance, the space number (or short name) by IfcSpace.Name, the space name (or long name) by IfcSpace:LongName, and the description (or comments) by IfcSpace.Description. Actual space quantities, like space perimeter, space area and space volume are provided by IfcElementQuantity, and space classification according to national building code by IfcClassificationReference. The level above zero (relative to the building) for the slab row construction is provided by the IfcBuildingStorey.Elevation, the level above zero (relative to the building) for the floor finish is provided by the IfcSpace.ElevationWithFlooring.</Definition>
  <Applicability />
  <ApplicableClasses>
    <ClassName>IfcSpace</ClassName>
  </ApplicableClasses>
  <ApplicableTypeValue>IfcSpace</ApplicableTypeValue>
  <PropertyDefs>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="a81efd00d20811e1800000215ad4efdf">
      <Name>Reference</Name>
      <Definition>Reference ID for this specified type in this project (e.g. type 'A-1'). Used to store the non-classification driven internal project type.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcIdentifier" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Raumtyp</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Reference</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Reference</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">参照記号</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ko-KR">참조 ID</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Bezeichnung zur Zusammenfassung gleichartiger Räume zu einem Raumtyp (auch Funktionstyp genannt). Alternativ zum Namen des "Typobjekts", insbesondere wenn die Software keine Raumtypen als Typobjekte unterstützt.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Référence à l'identifiant d'un type spécifié dans le contexte du projet (exemple : "type A1"). Utilisé pour enregistrer un type sans recourir à une classification.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">このプロジェクトにおける参照記号(例：A-1)。分類コードではなく内部で使用されるプロジェクトタイプとして使用されるもの。</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ko-KR">이 프로젝트의 참조 ID (예 : A-1). 분류 코드가 아닌 내부에서 사용되는 프로젝트 형식으로 사용됩니다.</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="f7fdc400d20811e1800000215ad4efdf">
      <Name>IsExternal</Name>
      <Definition>Indication whether the element is designed for use in the exterior (TRUE) or not (FALSE). If (TRUE) it is an external element and faces the outside of the building.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcBoolean" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">IstAußenraum</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Is External</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Est extérieur</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">外部区分</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe, ob dieser Raum ein Aussenaum ist (JA) oder ein Innenraum (NEIN).</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Indique si l'élément est conçu pour être utilisé à l'extérieur (VRAI) ou non (FAUX). Si VRAI, c'est un élément extérieur qui donne sur l'extérieur du bâtiment.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">外部の部材かどうかを示すブーリアン値。もしTRUEの場合、外部の部材で建物の外側に面している。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="00ee9580d20911e1800000215ad4efdf">
      <Name>GrossPlannedArea</Name>
      <Definition>Total planned gross area for the space. Used for programming the space.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcAreaMeasure" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Gross Planned Area</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Surface programmée brute</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">計画グロス面積</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ko-KR">계획 그로스 면적</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Surface programmée brute totale de la pièce. Telle que définie lors de la programmation.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">計画されたグロス面積。建物計画に際に使用。</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ko-KR">객실의 총 계획 면적 글로스. 공간 계획시 사용된다.</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="06e47680d20911e1800000215ad4efdf">
      <Name>NetPlannedArea</Name>
      <Definition>Total planned net area for the space. Used for programming the space.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcAreaMeasure" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Net Planned Area</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Surface programmée nette</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">計画ネット面積</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ko-KR">계획 인터넷 면적</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Surface programmée nette totale de la pièce. Telle que définie lors de la programmation.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">計画されたネット面積。建物計画に際に使用。（通常は、柱型等を抜いた面積となる）</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ko-KR">객실의 총 계획 인터넷 공간이 있습니다. 공간 계획시 사용된다.</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="0d72ee00d20911e1800000215ad4efdf">
      <Name>PubliclyAccessible</Name>
      <Definition>Indication whether this space (in case of e.g., a toilet) is designed to serve as a publicly accessible space, e.g., for a public toilet (TRUE) or not (FALSE).</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcBoolean" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">öffentlich zugänglich</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Publicly Accessible</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">AccessibleAuPublic</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">公共アクセス可能性</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ko-KR">공공 액세스 가능성</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe, ob dieser Raum (wie z.B. eine Toilette) öffentlich zugänglich sein soll (JA) oder nicht (NEIN).</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Indique si l'espace (par exemple des toilettes) est conçu pour être un espace accessible au public (TRUE) ou non (FALSE).</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">この部屋（空間）が公共アクセス空間かどうかを示すブーリアン値。例：公共トイレの場合TRUE。</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ko-KR">이 방 (공간)이 공공 액세스 공간 여부를 나타내는 부울 값입니다. 예 : 공공 화장실의 경우 TRUE.</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="1499fc00d20911e1800000215ad4efdf">
      <Name>HandicapAccessible</Name>
      <Definition>Indication whether this space (in case of e.g., a toilet) is designed to serve as an accessible space for handicapped people, e.g., for a public toilet (TRUE) or not (FALSE). This information is often used to declare the need for access for the disabled and for special design requirements of this space.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcBoolean" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">behindertengerecht zugänglich</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Handicap Accessible</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">AccessibleHandicapes</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">ハンディキャップアクセス可能性</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ko-KR">핸디캡 액세스 가능성</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe, ob dieser Raum (wie z.B. eine Toilette) behindertengerecht zugänglich sein soll (JA) oder nicht (NEIN).</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Indique si l'élément est conçu pour être accessible aux handicapés (VRAI) ou non (FAUX). Cette information est souvent utilisée pour déclarer la nécessité d'un accès pour handicapés ou pour des contraintes spéciales de conception.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">この部屋（空間）がハンディキャップ者向けの空間かどうかを示すブーリアン値。例：公共トイレの場合TRUE。この情報は、障害者向け利用の必要性や特別なデザインの必要性を示すために利用される。</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ko-KR">이 방 (공간)이 핸디캡을위한 공간 여부를 나타내는 부울 값입니다. 예 : 공공 화장실의 경우 TRUE. 이 정보는 장애인을위한 이용의 필요성과 특별한 디자인의 필요성을 나타내기 위해 사용된다.</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
  </PropertyDefs>
  <PsetDefinitionAliases>
    <PsetDefinitionAlias lang="en" />
    <PsetDefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Définition de l'IAI : propriétés communes à la définition de toutes les instances de la classe IfcSpace. Veuillez noter que plusieurs attributs sont portés par l'instance IfcSpace : le numéro de la pièce ou le nom court (IfcSpace.Name), le nom ou nom long (IfcSpace:LongName) et la description ou des commentaires (IfcSpace.Description). Les quantités comme le périmètre, la surface et le volume de la pièce sont fournis par des instances de IfcElementQuantity, et la référence à une classification nationale par IfcClassificationReference. L'élévation de la dalle relativement au niveau de référence du bâtiment est fourni par IfcBuildingStorey.Elevation.  L'élévation du plancher relativement au niveau de référence du bâtiment est fourni par IfcSpace.ElevationWithFlooring.</PsetDefinitionAlias>
    <PsetDefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">IfcSpaceに関する共通プロパティセット定義。以下の属性値に関しては、IfcSpaceオブジェクトの属性に設定する。部屋番号はIfcSite.Name、部屋名称はIfcSite.LongName、部屋に関する記述はIfcSite.Description。部屋（空間）に関する周囲長、面積、体積などの数量値は、IfcElementQuantitiesによって設定する。部屋（空間）に関する分類コードはIfcClassificationReferenceによって設定する。スラブに対するレベルはIfcBuildingStorey.Elevationによって与えられる。床仕上げに対するレベルはIfcSpace.ElevationWithFlooringによって与えられる。</PsetDefinitionAlias>
  </PsetDefinitionAliases>
</PropertySetDef>