<?xml version="1.0"?>
<QtoSetDef xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://buildingSMART-tech.org/xml/psd/PSD_IFC4.xsd">
  <IfcVersion version="IFC4" />
  <Name>Qto_SpaceBaseQuantities</Name>
  <Definition>Base quantities that are common to the definition of all occurrences of spaces.</Definition>
  <Applicability />
  <ApplicableClasses>
    <ClassName>IfcSpace</ClassName>
  </ApplicableClasses>
  <ApplicableTypeValue>IfcSpace</ApplicableTypeValue>
  <QtoDefs>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>Height</Name>
      <Definition>Total height (from base slab without flooring to ceiling without suspended ceiling) for this space (measured from top of slab below to bottom of slab above). To be provided only if the space has a constant height.</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_LENGTH</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Höhe</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Height</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">高さ</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamte Höhe des Raums, von Rohboden zur Rohdecke, wird nur angegeben wenn der Raum eine konstante Höhe hat.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の高さ。床スラブから天井までの高さ。つりさげ天井は含まない。下の床の上面から、上の床の下面までの距離となる。部屋が一定の高さを持っているときにのみ与えられる値。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>FinishCeilingHeight</Name>
      <Definition>Height of the suspended ceiling (from top of flooring to the bottom of the suspended ceiling). To be provided only if the space has a suspended ceiling with constant height.</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_LENGTH</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Lichte Höhe</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Finish Ceiling Height</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">天井仕上げ高さ</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Höhe der Unterdecke im Raum, vom Fertigboden zur Unterkante der Unterdecke, wird nur angegeben wenn der Raum ein konstante Unterdeckenhöhe hat.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">つりさげ天井の高さ。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>FinishFloorHeight</Name>
      <Definition>Height of the flooring (from base slab without flooring to the flooring height). To be provided only if the space has a constant flooring height.</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_LENGTH</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Fussboden Höhe</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Finish Floor Height</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">床仕上げ高さ</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Höhe des Fußbodenaufbaus im Raum, von Rohboden zum Fertigboden, wird nur angegeben wenn der Raum einen konstanten Fußbodenaufbau hat.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">床仕上げの高さ。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>GrossPerimeter</Name>
      <Definition>Gross perimeter at the floor level of this space. It all sides of the space, including those parts of the perimeter that are created by virtual boundaries and openings (like doors).</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_LENGTH</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Umfang Brutto</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Gross Perimeter</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">周辺長</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamter Umfang des Raumes, ohne Aubzug von Öffnungen (z.B. Türen).</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の周辺長。ドアや仮想的な境界なども含めた周辺長。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>NetPerimeter</Name>
      <Definition>Net perimeter at the floor level of this space. It excludes those parts of the perimeter that are created by by virtual boundaries and openings (like doors). It is the measurement used for skirting boards and may includes the perimeter of internal fixed objects like columns.</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_LENGTH</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Umfang Netto</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Net Perimeter</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">正味周辺長</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamter Unfang, der normalerweise mit einem Sockel versehen wird, d.h. mit Abzug von Türen aber einschlieslich innerer Umfänge z.B. an Stützen.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の正味の周辺長。ドアや仮想的な境界は含めない。幅木等の計測に使用する長さ。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>GrossFloorArea</Name>
      <Definition>Sum of all floor areas covered by the space. It includes the area covered by elementsinside the space (columns, inner walls, etc.) and excludes the area covered by wall claddings. </Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_AREA</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Bodenfläche Brutto</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Gross Floor Area</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">床面積</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamte Bodenfläche eines Raumes, unabhängig von der Raumhöhe. Öffnungen im Boden werden nicht abgezogen.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の床面積。柱や内部壁などを含んだ面積。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>NetFloorArea</Name>
      <Definition>Sum of all usable floor areas covered by the space. It excludes the area covered  by elements inside the space (columns, inner walls, built-in's etc.), slab openings, or other protruding elements. Varying heights are not taking into account (i.e. no reduction for areas under a minimum headroom).</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_AREA</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Bodenfläche Netto</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Net Floor Area</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">正味床面積</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamte Bodenfläche eines Raumes, unabhängig von der Raumhöhe. Alle Öffnungen im Boden, unabhängig von Ihrer Größe, werden abgezogen.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の床面積。柱や内部壁などを含まない面積。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>GrossWallArea</Name>
      <Definition>Sum of all wall (and other vertically bounding elements, like columns) areas bounded by the space. It includes the area covered by elements inside the wall area (doors, windows, other openings, etc.).</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_AREA</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Senkrechte Fläche Brutto</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Gross Wall Area</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">壁面積</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamte senkrechte Fläche in einem Raum ohne Abzug von Öffnungen. Virtuelle Begrenzungen sind nicht zu berücksichtigen.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋を構成する壁の面積。壁に含まれているドア、窓なども含む面積。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>NetWallArea</Name>
      <Definition>Sum of all wall (and other vertically bounding elements, like columns) areas bounded by the space. It excludes the area covered by elements inside the wall area (doors, windows, other openings, etc.).</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_AREA</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Senkrechte Fläche Netto</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Net Wall Area</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">正味壁面積</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamte senkrechte Fläche in einem Raum mit Abzug von Öffnungen. Virtuelle Begrenzungen sind nicht zu berücksichtigen.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋を構成する壁の面積で、壁に含まれているドア、窓などを含まない面積。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>GrossCeilingArea</Name>
      <Definition>Sum of all ceiling areas of the space. It includes the area covered by elementsinside the space (columns, inner walls, etc.). The ceiling area is the real (and not the projected) area (e.g. in case of sloped ceilings).</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_AREA</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Deckenfläche Brutto</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Gross Ceiling Area</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">天井面積</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamte Deckenfläche eines Raumes, unabhängig von der Raumhöhe. Öffnungen beispielsweise für Dachfenster oder Treppen werden nicht abgezogen. Es ist immer die wahre (nicht die projezierte) Fläche für Dachschrägen.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の天井面積。柱や内部壁などを含んだ面積。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>NetCeilingArea</Name>
      <Definition>Sum of all ceiling areas of the space. It excludes the area covered by elementsinside the space (columns, inner walls, etc.). The ceiling area is the real (and not the projected) area (e.g. in case of sloped ceilings).</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_AREA</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Deckenfläche Netto</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Net Ceiling Area</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">正味天井面積</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamte Deckenfläche eines Raumes unabhängig von der Raumhöhe. Öffnungen beispielsweise für Dachfenster oder Treppen werden abgezogen.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の天井面積。柱や内部壁などを含まない面積。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>GrossVolume</Name>
      <Definition>Gross volume enclosed by the space, including the volume of construction elements inside the space.</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_VOLUME</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Bruttovolumen</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Gross Volume</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">体積</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamtes Volumen eines Raumes ohne Abzüge von Einbauteilen (z.B. im Raum stehende Stützen, Balken, feste Einbauteile).</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の体積。部屋に含む部材を含む体積。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
    <QtoDef>
      <Name>NetVolume</Name>
      <Definition>Net volume enclosed by the space, excluding the volume of construction elements inside the space.</Definition>
      <QtoType>Q_VOLUME</QtoType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Nettovolumen</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Net Volume</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">正味体積</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Gesamtes Volumen eines Raumes mit Abzug von Einbauteilen (z.B. im Raum stehende Stützen, Balken, feste Einbauteile)..</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の体積。部屋に含む部材を含まない体積。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </QtoDef>
  </QtoDefs>
  <QtoDefinitionAliases>
    <QtoDefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Basismengen für alle Räume</QtoDefinitionAlias>
    <QtoDefinitionAlias lang="en" />
    <QtoDefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋に関わる共通の基本数量情報の定義。</QtoDefinitionAlias>
  </QtoDefinitionAliases>
</QtoSetDef>