<?xml version="1.0"?>
<PropertySetDef xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" ifdguid="7e5e0c89424f46bfa2bbcd0cf72e03c4" templatetype="PSET_TYPEDRIVENOVERRIDE" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://buildingSMART-tech.org/xml/psd/PSD_IFC4.xsd">
  <IfcVersion version="IFC4x3_RC4" />
  <Name>Pset_SpaceCoveringRequirements</Name>
  <Definition>Properties common to the definition of covering requirements of IfcSpace. Those properties define the requirements coming from a space program in early project phases and can later be used to define the room book information, if such coverings are not modeled explicitly as covering elements.</Definition>
  <Applicability />
  <ApplicableClasses>
    <ClassName>IfcSpace</ClassName>
  </ApplicableClasses>
  <ApplicableTypeValue>IfcSpace</ApplicableTypeValue>
  <PropertyDefs>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="bfd1f6a6ca08440899165d31dda04831">
      <Name>FloorCovering</Name>
      <Definition>Label to indicate the material or finish of the space flooring. The label is used for room book information and often displayed in room stamp.

The material information is provided in absence of an IfcCovering (type=FLOORING) object with own shape representation and material assignment. In case of inconsistency the material assigned to IfcCovering elements takes precedence.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcLabel" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Bodenbelag</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Floor Covering</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">RevetementSol</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">床仕上げ</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe des Materials für den Bodenbelag. Diese Angabe wird im Raumbuch verwendet und oft im Raumstempel angezeigt.

Die Materialangabe wird übernommen, wenn kein eigenes Bekleidungsobjekt (IfcCovering mit PredefinedType = FLOORING) für den Bodenbelag dem Raum zugeordnet ist. Bei Inkonsistenzen (wenn beides gegeben ist), hat die Materialangabe des zugeordneten Bekleidungsobjekts Priorität.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Indication sur la nature du revêtement de sol […]. L'information sur le matériau est fournie en l'absence d'un objet de la classe IfcCovering (Type=FLOORING) avec sa propre représentation de forme et une assignation à un matériau. En cas d'incohérence, c'est le matériau assigné à l'instance de IfcCovering qui prime.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の床材質または仕上げに関するラベル（識別情報）。このラベル名は部屋リスト情報や部屋情報表示の際に利用される。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="9650c4d3c07f4ccc9fd8147b099f0939">
      <Name>FloorCoveringThickness</Name>
      <Definition>Thickness of the material layer(s) for the space flooring.  

The thickness information is provided in absence of an IfcCovering (type=FLOORING) object with own shape representation. In cases of inconsistency between the geometric parameters of an assigned IfcCovering and this attached property, the geometric parameters take precedence.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcPositiveLengthMeasure" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Dicke des Bodenbelags</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Floor Covering Thickness</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Epaisseur du revêtement de sol</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">床仕上げ材厚</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe der Dicke der Materialschichten für den Bodenbelag. 

Der Dickenparameter wird übernommen, wenn kein eigenes Bekleidungsobjekt (IfcCovering mit PredefinedType = FLOORING) für den Bodenbelag dem Raum zugeordnet ist. Bei Inkonsistenzen (wenn beides gegeben ist), hat die Materialdicke des zugeordneten Bekleidungsobjekts Priorität.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Epaisseur de la couche de matériau constituant le revêtement de sol. Cette information sur le matériau est fournie en l'absence d'un objet de la classe IfcCovering (Type=FLOORING) avec sa propre représentation de forme. En cas d'incohérence entre les paramètres géométriques de l'instance de IfcCovering et cette propriété, ce sont les paramètres géométriques qui priment.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の床に関する材質層の厚さ。

形状表現を持つIfcCovering(type=FLOORING)オブジェクトが存在しない場合に与えられる厚さ情報。IfcCoveringの幾何形状パラメータとこのプロパティ値が一致しない場合、幾何形状パラメータの値を優先する。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="69193a7f647f4526bd7f1d3b9fdd1a9e">
      <Name>WallCovering</Name>
      <Definition>Label to indicate the material or finish of the space flooring. The label is used for room book information and often displayed in room stamp.

The material information is provided in absence of an IfcCovering (type=CLADDING) object with own shape representation and material assignment. In case of inconsistency the material assigned to IfcCovering elements takes precedence.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcLabel" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Wandbekleidung</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Wall Covering</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">RevetementMur</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">壁仕上げ</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe des Materials für die Wandbekleidung, oder den Wandbelag Diese Angabe wird im Raumbuch verwendet und oft im Raumstempel angezeigt.

Die Materialangabe wird übernommen, wenn kein eigenes Bekleidungsobjekt (IfcCovering mit PredefinedType = CLADDING) für die Wandbekleidung dem Raum zugeordnet ist. Bei Inkonsistenzen (wenn beides gegeben ist), hat die Materialangabe des zugeordneten Bekleidungsobjekts Priorität.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Indication sur la nature du revêtement de mur […]. L'information sur le matériau est fournie en l'absence d'un objet de la classe IfcCovering (Type=CLADDING) avec sa propre représentation de forme et une assignation à un matériau. En cas d'incohérence, c'est le matériau assigné à l'instance de IfcCovering qui prime.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の壁材質または仕上げに関するラベル（識別情報）。このラベル名は部屋リスト情報や部屋情報表示の際に利用される。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="44c775b14a0d46c58ad8c7e36c34a349">
      <Name>WallCoveringThickness</Name>
      <Definition>Thickness of the material layer(s) for the space cladding.  

The thickness information is provided in absence of an IfcCovering (type=CLADDING) object with own shape representation. In cases of inconsistency between the geometric parameters of an assigned IfcCovering and this attached property, the geometric parameters take precedence.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcPositiveLengthMeasure" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Dicke der Wandbekleidung</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Wall Covering Thickness</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Epaisseur du revêtement de mur</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">壁仕上げ厚</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe der Dicke der Materialschichten für die Wandbekleidung. 

Der Dickenparameter wird übernommen, wenn kein eigenes Bekleidungsobjekt (IfcCovering mit PredefinedType = CLADDING) für die Wandbekleidung dem Raum zugeordnet ist. Bei Inkonsistenzen (wenn beides gegeben ist), hat die Materialdicke des zugeordneten Bekleidungsobjekts Priorität.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Epaisseur de la couche de matériau constituant le revêtement de mur. Cette information sur le matériau est fournie en l'absence d'un objet de la classe IfcCovering (Type=CLADDING) avec sa propre représentation de forme. En cas d'incohérence entre les paramètres géométriques de l'instance de IfcCovering et cette propriété, ce sont les paramètres géométriques qui priment.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の壁に関する材質層の厚さ。

形状表現を持つIfcCovering(type=CLADDING)オブジェクトが存在しない場合に与えられる厚さ情報。IfcCoveringの幾何形状パラメータとこのプロパティ値が一致しない場合、幾何形状パラメータの値を優先する。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="da83c4235c1d40aba9510f6abe2412f6">
      <Name>CeilingCovering</Name>
      <Definition>Label to indicate the material or finish of the space flooring. The label is used for room book information and often displayed in room stamp.

The material information is provided in absence of an IfcCovering (type=CEILING) object with own shape representation and material assignment. In case of inconsistency the material assigned to IfcCovering elements takes precedence.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcLabel" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Deckenbekleidung</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Ceiling Covering</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">RevetementPlafond</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">天井仕上げ</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe des Materials für die Deckenbekleidung oder den Deckenbelag (bzw. der Unterdecke). Diese Angabe wird im Raumbuch verwendet und oft im Raumstempel angezeigt.

Die Materialangabe wird übernommen, wenn kein eigenes Bekleidungsobjekt (IfcCovering mit PredefinedType = CEILING) für die Deckenbekleidung dem Raum zugeordnet ist. Bei Inkonsistenzen (wenn beides gegeben ist), hat die Materialangabe des zugeordneten Bekleidungsobjekts Priorität.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Indication sur la nature du revêtement de plafond […]. L'information sur le matériau est fournie en l'absence d'un objet de la classe IfcCovering (Type=CEILING) avec sa propre représentation de forme et une assignation à un matériau. En cas d'incohérence, c'est le matériau assigné à l'instance de IfcCovering qui prime.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の天井材質または仕上げに関するラベル（識別情報）。このラベル名は部屋リスト情報や部屋情報表示の際に利用される。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="abdab367fcc64b08b03d584baeb819c8">
      <Name>CeilingCoveringThickness</Name>
      <Definition>Thickness of the material layer(s) for the space ceiling.  

The thickness information is provided in absence of an IfcCovering (type=CEILING) object with own shape representation. In cases of inconsistency between the geometric parameters of an assigned IfcCovering and this attached property, the geometric parameters take precedence.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcPositiveLengthMeasure" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Dicke der Deckenbekleidung</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Ceiling Covering Thickness</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Epaisseur du revêtement de plafond</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">天井仕上げ厚</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe der  Dicke der Materialschichten für die Deckenbekleidung. 

Der Dickenparameter wird übernommen, wenn kein eigenes Bekleidungsobjekt (IfcCovering mit PredefinedType = CEILING) für die Deckenbekleidung dem Raum zugeordnet ist. Bei Inkonsistenzen (wenn beides gegeben ist), hat die Materialdicke des zugeordneten Bekleidungsobjekts Priorität.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Epaisseur de la couche de matériau constituant le revêtement de sol. Cette information sur le matériau est fournie en l'absence d'un objet de la classe IfcCovering (Type=CEILING) avec sa propre représentation de forme. En cas d'incohérence entre les paramètres géométriques de l'instance de IfcCovering et cette propriété, ce sont les paramètres géométriques qui priment.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の天井に関する材質層の厚さ。

形状表現を持つIfcCovering(type=CEILING)オブジェクトが存在しない場合に与えられる厚さ情報。IfcCoveringの幾何形状パラメータとこのプロパティ値が一致しない場合、幾何形状パラメータの値を優先する。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="6d6b4d00a2234b90b4eb1901ca5be2b5">
      <Name>SkirtingBoard</Name>
      <Definition>Label to indicate the material or construction of the skirting board around the space flooring. The label is used for room book information.

The material information is provided in absence of an IfcCovering (type=SKIRTINGBOARD) object with own shape representation and material assignment. In case of inconsistency the material assigned to IfcCovering elements takes precedence.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcLabel" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Sockelleiste</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Skirting Board</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Matériau de la plinthe</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">幅木材</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe des Materials für die Sockelleiste. Diese Angabe wird im Raumbuch verwendet.

Die Materialangabe wird übernommen, wenn kein eigenes Bekleidungsobjekt (IfcCovering mit PredefinedType = SKIRTINGBOARD) für die Sockelleiste dem Raum zugeordnet ist. Bei Inkonsistenzen (wenn beides gegeben ist), hat die Materialangabe des zugeordneten Bekleidungsobjekts Priorität.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の床の周りにある幅木の材質または施工に関するラベル（識別情報）。ラベル名は部屋リスト情報に使用される。

形状表現を持つIfcCovering (type=SKIRTINGBOARD)オブジェクトが存在しない場合に与えられる材質情報。IfcCoveringの材質情報とこのプロパティ値が一致しない場合、IfcCoveringに与えられている材質情報を優先する。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="af1249f71eb24579aaec871aa4a6287b">
      <Name>SkirtingBoardHeight</Name>
      <Definition>Height of the skirting board.

The height information is provided in absence of an IfcCovering (type=SKIRTINGBOARD) object with own shape representation and material assignment. In case of inconsistency the height assigned to IfcCovering elements takes precedence.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcPositiveLengthMeasure" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Höhe der Sockelleite</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Skirting Board Height</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Hauteur de la plinthe</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">幅木材高</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe der  Höhe der umlaufenden Sockelleiste. 

Der Höhenparameter wird übernommen, wenn kein eigenes Bekleidungsobjekt (IfcCovering mit PredefinedType = SKIRTINGBOARD) für die Sockelleiste dem Raum zugeordnet ist. Bei Inkonsistenzen (wenn beides gegeben ist), hat die Höhe des zugeordneten Bekleidungsobjekts Priorität.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の幅木の高さ。

形状表現を持つIfcCovering(type=SKIRTINGBOARD)オブジェクトが存在しない場合に与えられる厚さ情報。IfcCoveringの幾何形状パラメータとこのプロパティ値が一致しない場合、幾何形状パラメータの値を優先する。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="3f9ca576246247ff8bdca254b651a15a">
      <Name>Molding</Name>
      <Definition>Label to indicate the material or construction of the molding around the space ceiling. The label is used for room book information.

The material information is provided in absence of an IfcCovering (type=MOLDING) object with own shape representation and material assignment. In case of inconsistency the material assigned to IfcCovering elements takes precedence.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcLabel" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Gesims</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Molding</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Matériau de la moulure</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">廻縁</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe des Materials für das Gesims (Deckenkante). Diese Angabe wird im Raumbuch verwendet.

Die Materialangabe wird übernommen, wenn kein eigenes Bekleidungsobjekt (IfcCovering mit PredefinedType = MOLDING) für das Gesims dem Raum zugeordnet ist. Bei Inkonsistenzen (wenn beides gegeben ist), hat die Materialangabe des zugeordneten Bekleidungsobjekts Priorität.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の廻縁の材質または施工に関するラベル（識別情報）。ラベル名は部屋リスト情報に使用される。

形状表現を持つIfcCovering (type=MOLDING)オブジェクトが存在しない場合に与えられる材質情報。IfcCoveringの材質情報とこのプロパティ値が一致しない場合、IfcCoveringに与えられている材質情報を優先する。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="1e0092682e5347b2b2c5050bd03ee111">
      <Name>MoldingHeight</Name>
      <Definition>Height of the molding.

The height information is provided in absence of an IfcCovering (type=MOLDING) object with own shape representation and material assignment. In case of inconsistency the height assigned to IfcCovering elements takes precedence.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcPositiveLengthMeasure" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Höhe des Gesims</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Molding Height</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Hauteur de la moulure</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">廻縁高</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe der  Höhe des umlaufenden Gesims (Deckenkante). 

Der Höhenparameter wird übernommen, wenn kein eigenes Bekleidungsobjekt (IfcCovering mit PredefinedType = MOLDING) für das Gesims dem Raum zugeordnet ist. Bei Inkonsistenzen (wenn beides gegeben ist), hat die Höhe des zugeordneten Bekleidungsobjekts Priorität.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">部屋の廻縁の高さ。

形状表現を持つIfcCovering(type=MOLDING)オブジェクトが存在しない場合に与えられる厚さ情報。IfcCoveringの幾何形状パラメータとこのプロパティ値が一致しない場合、幾何形状パラメータの値を優先する。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="8650a689ba064df69f052a87ab070f02">
      <Name>ConcealedFlooring</Name>
      <Definition>Indication whether this space is designed to have a concealed flooring space (TRUE) or not (FALSE). A concealed flooring space is normally meant to be the space beneath a raised floor.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcBoolean" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Installationsboden</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Concealed Flooring</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">FauxPlancher</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">隠蔽床</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe, ob dieser Raum mit einem aufgeständerten Fußboden ausgestattet ist (JA), oder nicht (NEIN).</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Indique si la pièce comprend un faux plancher (VRAI) ou non (FAUX)</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">この部屋（空間）が隠蔽された床空間を持つように設計されているかどうかを示すブーリアン値。隠蔽された床空間とは、上げ床の下の空間。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="56029141a7c040c4aef51a242fa1611f">
      <Name>ConcealedFlooringOffset</Name>
      <Definition>Distance between the floor slab and the floor covering, often used for cables and other installations. Often referred to as raised flooring.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcNonNegativeLengthMeasure" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases />
      <DefinitionAliases />
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="7502fd34b7fa494280c610aec4787043">
      <Name>ConcealedCeiling</Name>
      <Definition>Indication whether this space is designed to have a concealed flooring space (TRUE) or not (FALSE). A concealed ceiling space is normally meant to be the space between a slab and a ceiling.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcBoolean" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Installationsdecke</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Concealed Ceiling</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">FauxPlafond</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="ja-JP">隠蔽天井</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Angabe, ob dieser Raum mit einer Installationsdecke (abgehängten Decke) ausgestattet ist (JA), oder nicht (NEIN).</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Indique si la pièce comprend un faux plafond (VRAI) ou non (FAUX)</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">この部屋（空間）が隠蔽された天井空間を持つように設計されているかどうかを示すブーリアン値。隠蔽された天井空間とは、スラブと天井の間の空間。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="a7d072c8df3245bd9c1b9424d7f35a87">
      <Name>ConcealedCeilingOffset</Name>
      <Definition>Distance between the upper floor slab and the suspended ceiling, often used for distribution systems. Often referred to as plenum.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcNonNegativeLengthMeasure" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases />
      <DefinitionAliases />
    </PropertyDef>
  </PropertyDefs>
  <PsetDefinitionAliases>
    <PsetDefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Eigenschaften der Bekleidungen des Raumes.

Diese Eigenschaften werden als Anforderungen in frühen Phasen im Raumprogramm geführt und können für spätere Phasen als Informationen für das Raumbuch dienen, falls die Bekleidungen nicht als eigenständige Elemente angelegt werden.</PsetDefinitionAlias>
    <PsetDefinitionAlias lang="en" />
    <PsetDefinitionAlias lang="ja-JP">IfcSpace（部屋）の仕上げ(Covering)の共通属性。プロジェクト初期の空間計画からの仕上げ要求仕様情報を設定する。もし。Coveringオブジェクトが生成されていない場合は、このプロパティセットの情報は仕上げ表作成に使用することができる。</PsetDefinitionAlias>
  </PsetDefinitionAliases>
</PropertySetDef>