<?xml version="1.0"?>
<PropertySetDef xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" ifdguid="f5cb4380d1cf11e1800000215ad4efdf" templatetype="PSET_TYPEDRIVENOVERRIDE" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://buildingSMART-tech.org/xml/psd/PSD_IFC4.xsd">
  <IfcVersion version="IFC4x3_RC4" />
  <Name>Pset_CoveringCeiling</Name>
  <Definition>Properties common to the definition of all occurrence and type objects of covering with the predefined type set to CEILING.</Definition>
  <Applicability />
  <ApplicableClasses>
    <ClassName>IfcCovering/CEILING</ClassName>
  </ApplicableClasses>
  <ApplicableTypeValue>IfcCovering/CEILING</ApplicableTypeValue>
  <PropertyDefs>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="febc1500d1cf11e1800000215ad4efdf">
      <Name>Permeability</Name>
      <Definition>Ratio of the permeability of the ceiling.
The ration can be used to indicate an open ceiling (that enables identification of whether ceiling construction should be considered as impeding distribution of sprinkler water, light etc. from installations within the ceiling area).</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcNormalisedRatioMeasure" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Durchlässigkeit</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Permeability</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Perméabilité</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="zh-CN">渗透率</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Durchlässigkeit der Unterdecke als Faktor zwischen 0 Undurchlässig und 1 völlig durchlässig. Der Faktor kann zur Abschätzung genutzt werden, ob die Unterdecke zur Decke hin offen und durchlässig (für Licht, Wasser und Sicht) ist.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Ratio de perméabilité du plafond. Ce ratio peut être utilisé pour désigner un plafond ouvert (cela permet de savoir si la pose du plafond empêche la distribution de fluides à partir d'installations situées dans le faux plafond).</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="zh-CN">天花板的渗透比率。
该比率可用以表示开敞式天花板（表示天花板能否阻隔其内侧的喷淋水、光线等的）。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="04195f80d1d011e1800000215ad4efdf">
      <Name>TileLength</Name>
      <Definition>Length of ceiling tiles. The size information is provided in addition to the shape representation and the geometric parameters used within. In cases of inconsistency between the geometric parameters and the size properties, provided in the attached property set, the geometric parameters take precedence.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcPositiveLengthMeasure" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Deckenplattenlänge</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Tile Length</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Longueur des carreaux</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="zh-CN">面砖长度</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Länge der Unterdeckenplatten, oder -panele, die zur Verkleidung verwendet werden.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Longueur des carreaux de plafond. Cette propriété est donnée en complément de la représentation de la forme et des paramètres géométriques qui la déterminent. En cas d'incohérence entre ces paramètres géométriques et cette propriété, ce sont les paramètres géométriques qui priment.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="zh-CN">天花板面砖的长度。
该属性所提供的尺寸信息是对内部形状描述和几何参数的补充。如果几何参数与该属性所提供的尺寸属性不符，应以几何参数为准。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
    <PropertyDef ifdguid="0976aa00d1d011e1800000215ad4efdf">
      <Name>TileWidth</Name>
      <Definition>Width of ceiling tiles. The size information is provided in addition to the shape representation and the geometric parameters used within. In cases of inconsistency between the geometric parameters and the size properties, provided in the attached property set, the geometric parameters take precedence.</Definition>
      <PropertyType>
        <TypePropertySingleValue>
          <DataType type="IfcPositiveLengthMeasure" />
        </TypePropertySingleValue>
      </PropertyType>
      <NameAliases>
        <NameAlias lang="de-DE">Deckenplattenbreite</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="en">Tile Width</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="fr-FR">Largeur des carreaux</NameAlias>
        <NameAlias lang="zh-CN">面砖宽度</NameAlias>
      </NameAliases>
      <DefinitionAliases>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="de-DE">Breite der Unterdeckenplatten, oder -panele, die zur Verkleidung verwendet werden.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="en" />
        <DefinitionAlias lang="fr-FR">Largeur des carreaux de plafond. Cette propriété est donnée en complément de la représentation de la forme et des paramètres géométriques qui la déterminent. En cas d'incohérence entre ces paramètres géométriques et cette propriété, ce sont les paramètres géométriques qui priment.</DefinitionAlias>
        <DefinitionAlias lang="zh-CN">天花板面砖的宽度。
该属性所提供的尺寸信息是对内部形状描述和几何参数的补充。如果几何参数与该属性所提供的尺寸属性不符，应以几何参数为准。</DefinitionAlias>
      </DefinitionAliases>
    </PropertyDef>
  </PropertyDefs>
  <PsetDefinitionAliases>
    <PsetDefinitionAlias lang="en" />
    <PsetDefinitionAlias lang="zh-CN">所有PredefinedType设置为CEILING的IfcCovering实例的定义中通用的属性。</PsetDefinitionAlias>
  </PsetDefinitionAliases>
</PropertySetDef>